BUSINESS ANALYSIS AND REPORTING ANALYST Summary

Compliance investigator position which focuses on Anti-Money Laundering, Bank Secrecy Act, Fraud Investigations, KYC, OFAC and/or USA Patriot Act, that allows for the parlay of adaptable, analytical, communication, customer service, investigation, organizational, research, and restorative skills proven by six successful years in Anti-Money Laundering/Compliance and Fraud Investigations.

Highlights

- Adaptable
- Results Orientated
- Analytical
- Fraud Management
- Investigative
- Prioritize Work
- Restorative
- Strong Documentation Skills
- Ability to Multi-task
 Self-Starter

Skills

Ability to lead others in a proactive manner.

Ability to take ownership.

Proficient in Microsoft Excel.

Experience

Business Analysis and Reporting Analyst, 09/2014 to Current Jpmorgan Chase & Co. 1/4 Livonia, MI

Successfully analyzed KYC/Trigger alerts for the KYC/Trigger team.

Successfully Inspected and Repaired other analysts' work for the KYC/Trigger team.

AML Compliance Officer, 12/2013 to 09/2014 Wedbush Morgan Securities il/4 San Diego, CA

Effectively wrote procedures for the Manual Alert Analysis team.

Served as a backup to the International Cash Letters process.

Successfully completed various eRCM alerts in the testing phase.

Successfully completed the Global Pre-Paid, OFAC, and Travelers Checks/Money Orders processes on a weekly and monthly basis.

Successfully completed a Fortent cycle with high accuracy.

Triaged branch and non-branch referrals and subpoenas to be handled by their respective Lines of Business AML Investigators.

AML Compliance Officer, 08/2013 to 12/2013 Wedbush Morgan Securities i/4 Jersey City, NJ

Analyzed International Cash Letters based on 13 AML Red Flags.

Investigated Fortent Alerts for JPMorgan Chase Bank.

Successfully completed AML New Hire training at JPMorgan Chase.

Teller, 04/2013 to 08/2013 Farmers il/4 Monroe, IN

Cautiously handled large amounts of money.

Effectively managed banking transactions for retail banking clients.

Successfully prevented fraudulent activity.

Administrative Specialist III, 11/2012 to 03/2013 University Of Arkansas i1/4 Rison, AR

Analyzed police reports.

Completed tasks in a timely manner.

Filed payment voucher documents for FY 2013.

Issued payment vouchers to pay victims and their providers.

Researched documents for cases on the DELJIS system.

Served as a back-up to front-end operations for the Victims' Compensation Assistance Program.

Uploaded all FY 2013 claim forms into the CCVC database.

Compliance Analyst, 08/2012 to 11/2012 Vista Equity Partners il/4 Dearborn, MI

Reviewed criminal background reports and drug test results to analyze a candidate's employment eligibility.

Reviewed I-9 database to ensure all associates were in compliance with the Department of Homeland Security rules and regulations.

AML Compliance Officer, 11/2011 to 12/2011 Wedbush Morgan Securities il/4 Lake Oswego, OR

Analyzed clients' accounts for missing Know Your Customer information.

Ensured information on clients was correct for Know Your Customer.

Administrative Assistant, 09/2011 to 11/2011 Rollins, Inc i1/4 Urbandale, IA

Completed various mailouts for the organization.

Exercised ability to meet deadlines.

Successfully recovered 100% on past due publication accounts.

AML Compliance Analyst, 07/2011 to 08/2011 Guardian Life i1/4 Appleton, WI

Investigated/researched client information to identify clients which are "Politically Exposed Peopleâ€.

Proficient with using the LexisNexis and World Check databases.

Fraud Control Specialist, 03/2007 to 07/2011 Wilmington Trust Company i1/4 City, STATE

Served as First Contact for coworkers, clients, and law enforcement at Fraud Investigative Services Division.

Effectively investigated small-claim fraud.

Ensured all cases and paperwork were correctly filed.

Processed all restitution payments from various courts.

Prevented \$70,000 check-fraud loss in 2009.

Successfully recovered 99.6% of fraud losses over four years.

Fraud Detection Analyst, 09/2006 to 01/2007 Bank Of America il/4 City, STATE

Analyzed clients' credit card charge records for suspicious activity.

Verified suspicious activity upon detection with clients.

Cancelled clients' credit cards when fraudulent activity was verified.

Proficient with using the LexisNexis database.

Education

MBA: Organizational Leadership, 2012 Wilmington University il/4 City, State

MBA: Homeland Security, 2011 Wilmington University i½ City, State BBA: Business Administration, 2007 Wesley College i¼ City, State

Associate of Applied Science: Criminal Justice, 2004 Delaware Technical and Community College it/4 City, State